<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><wiki-page>
<author>admin</author>
<created>20150325175343</created>
<title>Variants</title>
<type>content</type>
<content><![CDATA[{section}
{column:width=68%}
1 $page.title
A ~~Variant~~ describes one product from a product line (i.e. a group of similar products with some features in common). In this space you can define Variants and manage their ~~Variant Specification Documents~~.

A Variant Specification Document is a specification Document generated for a Variant after its ~~Features~~ have been selected from the superset of all possible product Features, and the selection is valid according to configured ~~Restrictions~~. Variant Specification Documents can then be generated from ~~Master Specifications~~. They include only specifications that are relevant for one Variant, providing a complete specification for one product in a product line.

#info("Define a new Variant via the Variants sidebar. Include/exclude Features, and ensure that the Feature selection is valid.") 

1.1.1 OBJECTIVE
Manage the Variant Specification Documents for different Variants.

1.1.1  INPUT

[Master Specifications > Master Specifications.Home] - are Documents that contain all component specifications (for all the products in a product line).

 {portallink:/wiki/Features/Feature%20Model | addcontext=yes}Feature Model{portallink} - The Master Specifications are constrained to Features.


1.1.1 OUTPUT - VARIANTS
This section lists the Variants currently tracked in the system:

#foreach($v in $trackerService.queryWorkItems("type:variant AND (project.id:$page.project OR definitionProject:$page.project)","id"))
* {portallink:/wiki/Variants/Variant Report?variant=$v.project.id/$v.id|addcontext=yes} $v.id - $v.title {portallink} &nbsp;
#end

{column}


{column:width=32%}

{regiontitle}Actions{regiontitle}
{style:class=regiondescription}

<div>
{portallink:/workitem?form_mode=create&form_field_type=variant|addcontext=yes}<img src="/polarion/ria/images/wiki/NewVariant.png"/>{portallink}
</div>

{regiontitle}Guide{regiontitle}
{style:class=regiondescription}
Steps to define one product Variant in a product line:
{style}

1. *Create New Variant* \\ Create a new Work Item of type ~~Variant~~
1. *Select Features* \\ Select a Variant item and click the {Select Features} button. Make sure selection is valid by selecting Features based on their Variation Type.
1. *Generate Variant Specification Document* \\ Select Variant item and click the {Generate Documents} button. Select ~~Master Specification~~ as input and save result to the Variants space.
{column}
{section}]]></content>
</wiki-page>